<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-20T14:09:02+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GYAB</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">L’Eve future - Auguste de Villiers de L’Isle-Adam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/20/l-eve-future-auguste-de-villiers-de-l-isle-adam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="L’Eve future - Auguste de Villiers de L’Isle-Adam" /><published>2020-06-20T12:34:16+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T12:34:16+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/20/l-eve-future-auguste-de-villiers-de-l-isle-adam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/20/l-eve-future-auguste-de-villiers-de-l-isle-adam.html">&lt;p&gt;L’Eve future, second et dernier roman de Villiers de l’Isle-Adam, est publié en 1886, et bien des années séparent l’embryon de ce livre de sa publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J’ai apprécié cet ouvrage et d’autant plus que je n’en savais rien, je ne connaissais pas l’auteur et encore moins le titre de ce roman avant de le rajouter à ma “reading list”. Et cela me semble être la meilleure façon de découvrir une œuvre, quelle qu’elle soit. Et c’est désormais ainsi que je procède, que ce soit pour un livre, un film ou un album, ajouté dans des listes de plus en plus longues, et finalement tellement longues, qu’arriver au moment de lire, voir ou écouter, je ne sais souvent plus comment j’en suis arrivé à écouter la première piste, à lire la première page, à écouter ce premier dialogue. Je préfère en savoir le moins possible, à quoi bon. Les bandes-annonces, qui “spoilent” tout un film ou presque, sont de l’histoire ancienne, en tout cas pour moi. Tout comme les critiques, sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/&quot;&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt; par exemple. Je fais toutefois quelques exceptions, par exemple littéraire avec le blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juanasensio.com/&quot;&gt;Stalker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C’est sans surprise donc, que j’ai vite abandonné la lecture de l’introduction de L’Eve future, 80 pages quand même, écrites par une personne, qui se doit sans doute d’être connue, après tout seul son prénom et nom figurent, mais qui dans le cas contraire semble bien étrangère, ce qui ne pousse pas plus à la lecture. D’ailleurs, à quoi bon en apprendre autant avant d’entamer la lecture à proprement dite. Je l’ai tout de même lu après le roman à proprement parlé. Et si je trouve toujours qu’elle porte mal son nom, cette “introduction” n’en est pas moins indispensable. Google m’a permis d’apprendre que Nadine Satiat, l’auteure, est docteur en littérature comparée, et spécialiste du XIXe siècle, excusez du peu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/l_eve_future.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;L'Eve future couverture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roman de science-fiction écrit en pleine industrialisation, on y découvre Thomas Edison, créateur d’une machine qui n’est plus juste un outil pour l’homme mais son évolution, permettant de tendre vers la perfection de l’humanité. Cela sonne donc étrangement contemporain, avec l’avénement de l’intelligence artificielle et de la robotique, qui commence de nos jours par la destruction de millions d’emplois et d’ailleurs pas toujours &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200224095620/https://web.stanford.edu/~mww/webb_jmp.pdf&quot;&gt;ceux que l’on croit&lt;/a&gt;, et si l’&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c8-OeGYRFpI&quot;&gt;Artificial general intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, est encore loin, L’Eve future sera peut-être considéré comme un roman d’anticipation dans un futur plus ou moins proche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’attrait de pouvoir créer cette machine est de palier aux faiblesses de l’Homme et avant de la femme dans le cas de ce roman. L’auteur y décrit longuement les imperfections de la femme, imperfections incurables, ne pouvant être surpassées que par la création de cette machine. Et si la création d’Edison ne consent pas aux plaisirs charnels, de nos jours les prémisses de &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-51330261&quot;&gt;robots sexuels&lt;/a&gt; démontrent que l’industrie du sexe a été et restera à l’avant-garde de l’utilisation de nouvelles technologies.
Ce roman permet également de découvrir Menlo Park au New Jersey, la ville d’Edison, qui fait aujourd’hui bien pâle figure par rapport à sa grande soeur de l’autre côté du pays, siège de Facebook, de Thomas Edison à Mark Zuckerberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La fin du roman est compendieuse mais suffit pour ouvrir la réflexion sur le rôle de Dieu, sur l’écart entre le rêve et la réalité, particulièrement abyssale dans la vie de Villiers de l’Isle-Adam.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">L’Eve future, second et dernier roman de Villiers de l’Isle-Adam, est publié en 1886, et bien des années séparent l’embryon de ce livre de sa publication.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Be Not So Fearful</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/be-not-so-fearful.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Not So Fearful" /><published>2020-03-18T23:12:03+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-18T23:12:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/be-not-so-fearful</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/18/be-not-so-fearful.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I wanted to write this post. Almost two years in the making. But fortunately for this post, it’s never too late at it depends only on me, so it’s still up to date as it can be. Beyond the primary reason of this post, there’s a will to write more. There’s a lot of things that I’d like to write about but it’s just too easy to find a reason not to do it. I’m not competent enough, my English is not that good…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well back to the subject at hand, my experience tabbing a folk song by Bill Fay for guitar. To give a little context, I’ve been playing guitar off and on for more than 20 years now. And during that time, I’ve never really taken the time to get to play a song just by hearing it. Mostly because I’m lazy and also because it’s just too easy to find tabs on the internet, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ultimate-guitar.com/&quot;&gt;ultimate-guitar.com&lt;/a&gt;, I’m looking at you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I’m quite the guy when it comes to leaving things uncompleted. There’s always a good reason not to keep on with it and get to the finish line. Regarding this tab, it was probably a lack of will more than anything else. I’m pretty sure that what I’ve tabbed it’s good enough but the last 10% that had to be done were the most complicated, writing this post, posting the tab, recording myself playing it. But here I am today, writing about it, embedding a mp3 file of myself playing the song with the chords that I have found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to tab a song, I don’t really use a fixed method to find the chords, the melody or anything else. I start by looking for a few notes that sound good when I play them over the song. From there I try to find the tonic and then the first chords or two. I sometimes use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audacityteam.org/&quot;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt; to be able to focus on a small part and repeat it over and over again until I’m satisfied enough and I’m pretty sure to have found the rights chords or notes, or at least to be close enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could search for tips on Google on how to tab a song but I know that what I need to do right now, it’s just to take a bunch of songs and try to get two or three chords out of them. And to do that a certain amount of times so I can see myself improving which would get me even more motivated to continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first song that I tabbed is called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mJfca3ImjKc&quot;&gt;Be Not So Fearful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Bill Fay. It’s a very nice and not so complicated song when it comes to the guitar being played. You can find my tab here on &lt;a href=&quot;https://tabs.ultimate-guitar.com/tab/bill-fay/be-not-so-fearful-chords-3029630&quot;&gt;ultimate-guitar.com&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;/assets//be_not_so_fearful.mp3&quot;&gt;listen to a recording&lt;/a&gt; of myself playing in sync with the song in the background.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a long time since I wanted to write this post. Almost two years in the making. But fortunately for this post, it’s never too late at it depends only on me, so it’s still up to date as it can be. Beyond the primary reason of this post, there’s a will to write more. There’s a lot of things that I’d like to write about but it’s just too easy to find a reason not to do it. I’m not competent enough, my English is not that good…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Le Baiser au Lépreux (The Kiss to the Leper) by François Mauriac</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/19/le-baiser-au-lepreux-fran%C3%A7ois-mauriac.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Le Baiser au Lépreux (The Kiss to the Leper) by François Mauriac" /><published>2018-07-19T22:12:03+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T22:12:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/19/le-baiser-au-lepreux-fran%C3%A7ois-mauriac</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/19/le-baiser-au-lepreux-fran%C3%A7ois-mauriac.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Baiser au Lépreux&lt;/em&gt; (The Kiss to the Leper) is a novel by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fran%C3%A7ois_Mauriac&quot;&gt;François Mauriac&lt;/a&gt; published in 1922.  François Mauriac was a renowned french writer, member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acad%C3%A9mie_fran%C3%A7aise&quot;&gt;Académie Française&lt;/a&gt; and laureate of the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1952.  The Kiss to the Leper is a short novel, spanning just over one hundred pages but the style is remarkable, concise yet not rushed. Like the novel, the chapters are not long and can be almost assimilated to a scene in a play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/baiser_au_lepreux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Kiss to the Leper book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book follows the life of the Péloueyre family, and especially the son Jean, an ugly man, avoiding people at all costs and spending most of this time hunting or going to the church by himself, who is going to be married, following the action of the local priest, to an ingenuous woman named Noémi. The action takes place in a town in the south west of France, where François Mauriac was born and raised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The priest seems, at that time, to have a strong influence over the life of the town. People were more religious, especially in the countryside. So the priest was likely to know a lot of things as people were confessing to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of characters in the novel, which contains very few, contract tuberculosis, which was called the white plague in the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. It is estimated than over 10 millions people died from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tuberculosis&quot;&gt;tuberculosis&lt;/a&gt; in France during the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. One measure to counter this illness was to build sanatoriums, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TNlvqwXjBX4&quot;&gt;Paimio Sanatorium&lt;/a&gt; in Finland, completed in 1933 and designed by Alvar Aalto, which has recently even been nominated to become a UNESCO World Heritage Site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/alvar-aalto-federico-covre-paimio-sanatorium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paimio Sanatorium&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point during the novel, the main character, Jean, goes to Paris, mostly to escape from his wife. This trip seems extraordinary at the time. I can’t imagine what people in the 22&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century will think of today’s travel possibilities? “10 hours flight to get to Beijing, I just did that last week in 30 minutes!”. Maybe not so far off, as it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/29/16383048/elon-musk-spacex-rocket-transport-earth-travel&quot;&gt;has been proposed&lt;/a&gt; by Elon Musk last year. Wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Le Baiser au Lépreux (The Kiss to the Leper) is a novel by François Mauriac published in 1922. François Mauriac was a renowned french writer, member of the Académie Française and laureate of the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1952. The Kiss to the Leper is a short novel, spanning just over one hundred pages but the style is remarkable, concise yet not rushed. Like the novel, the chapters are not long and can be almost assimilated to a scene in a play.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No Direction Home - Bob Dylan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/30/no-direction-home-bob-dylan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Direction Home - Bob Dylan" /><published>2018-06-30T14:12:03+02:00</published><updated>2018-06-30T14:12:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/30/no-direction-home-bob-dylan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/30/no-direction-home-bob-dylan.html">&lt;p&gt;I was in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyon&quot;&gt;Lyon&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back and because of the rail strikes, there were no cheap high-speed train tickets available on the sunday night that I was going back to Paris. So I had to take an old train which took me from Lyon to the French capital in four hours and a half instead of less than two hours with a regular &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TGV&quot;&gt;TGV&lt;/a&gt;. At least, the scenery were quite splendid and the relative speed of the train did allow to really enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I still had to find ways to make the time pass and I did, watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0367555/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Direction Home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the documentary about Bob Dylan directed by Martin Scorsese. It was released in 2005 and is quite long, with a three hours length. The documentary depicts the journey of Bob Dylan from the time he came to New York City in 1961 to the his motorcycle accident in July 1966, just after the end of his European Tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m quite fond of Bob Dylan. I know most of the songs from his first albums, the ones that were released before 1966. I even got the chance to see him live in Nantes in 2010. It was not so good, to say the least, but it was still quite mesmerizing to be 20 meters away from this legend while he was singing &lt;em&gt;Mr Tambourine Man&lt;/em&gt;, even if it was miles away from his performance at the &lt;em&gt;Newport Folk Festival&lt;/em&gt; in 1964!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OeP4FFr88SQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentary is interesting, mostly thanks to the footage from back then, the recent interviews were not so compelling. Is it really meaningful to have people blabbering stories about what happened 40 years down the line? And I would have instead loved to know more about Bob Dylan’s life before he moved to NYC. Maybe it would have been a good idea to interview members of his family, even if I’m sure, they would have been quite reluctant to do so. But when Martin Scorsese is the one asking, it’s different right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was amazed by the fact that most of the songs from that time were recorded in a total uncanny way. Barely rehearsed and considered good enough to appear on the record after only one or two takes. I’ve never wrote a song but it seems quite extraordinary to have songs, that are still considered amongst the best ever recorded, even today, to have been recorded that way. It really shows the genius of Dylan at that period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, It’s quite sad to see that mainstream journalists were already completely ignorant and only interested by their thinking and not even trying to grasp the person that they were interviewing, here Bob Dylan, which found himself answering the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mnl5X5MQKTg&quot;&gt;stupidest questions&lt;/a&gt;, day after day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After watching this documentary, I’d clearly like to know more about the life of Bob Dylan so I have added his memoir &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chronicles:_Volume_One&quot;&gt;Chronicles: Volume One&lt;/a&gt; to my booklist. A review of this book can be expected shortly, but probably not before 2024 though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uCcc-XRAf5s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was in Lyon a few weeks back and because of the rail strikes, there were no cheap high-speed train tickets available on the sunday night that I was going back to Paris. So I had to take an old train which took me from Lyon to the French capital in four hours and a half instead of less than two hours with a regular TGV. At least, the scenery were quite splendid and the relative speed of the train did allow to really enjoy it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">L’Étrange Défaite (Strange Defeat) by Marc Bloch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/23/etrange-defaite-marc-bloch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="L’Étrange Défaite (Strange Defeat) by Marc Bloch" /><published>2018-04-23T00:12:03+02:00</published><updated>2018-04-23T00:12:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/23/etrange-defaite-marc-bloch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/23/etrange-defaite-marc-bloch.html">&lt;p&gt;As this is my first post, I just quickly want to explain what bring me to write it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be about reading. Because even if I don’t find myself reading all that much, I feel like I could at least get more out of the books I read. It’s easy, quite easier actually, to read a book without really taking the time to process the meaning of each sentence or paragraph and to turn one page after another without taking notes or think twice about something maybe not so easy to grasp in its entirety. Well that’s what I used to do at least! But I have decided to make some changes, and now take the time necessary to reflect at least once I will finish a book and write a few things down – and maybe an article like this one about it. By writing things down, I will try to summarize what I learned and thought of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is the first step towards creating a system that would help me better retain the informations or ideas that I found valuable in something that I read, let that be a book or an article on the Internet. Today, I sometimes highlight words, sentences, or paragraphs on my Kindle but I don’t really do much with them. The only thing I’m actually doing is adding the words I don’t know (either English or French), to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&quot;&gt;Anki account&lt;/a&gt;, a spaced repetition flashcard program, to learn them more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/strange-defeat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strange Defeat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book I’m going to introduce, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strange_Defeat&quot;&gt;“L’Étrange défaite”&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Strange Defeat&lt;/em&gt;), is a book written by Marc Bloch in July 1940, a month after France had surrendered to the Third Reich. Marc Bloch was a French historian, who fought in the trenches during the first World War and who was a captain during the short &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_France&quot;&gt;Battle of France&lt;/a&gt; in 1940. He would then joined the French Resistance in 1942 and fought until he was captured in 1944 by the Vichy police and handed over to the Gestapo. He was executed by a firing squad on the night of 16 June 1944, ten days after the Normandy landings. In this book, Bloch described what he witnessed during the Battle of France and also tried to explain how the Fall of France can have been so sudden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write this article, I am expanding a few notes I wrote quickly, on a small notebook, a few days after I finished reading this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first part of his book, Bloch described the French Army as unprepared but confident in its ability to fight the Wehrmacht. Even the rapid invasion of Poland by the German forces in September 1939 had no effect on the way French Generals were envisioning the coming conflict. “The Battle of France” would then only last 43 days, and demonstrated once again the implacable superiority of the German forces. Bloch, when he exposes the errors committed by the French, blames at numerous occasions the oldness of the people in charge of the French military. Stating that most young officers who hadn’t fought during the first World War had better insights that their superiors, for whom this new World War was not going to be so much different that the previous one. Bloch writes, a few pages later, than contrary to the French, “The Nazi Revolution put in command”, whether at the head of the army or of the state, men, whom because they were young and hadn’t been brainwashed, were more capable to understand “the surprising or the new”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloch, not only blames the French military but also condemns, on multiple occasions, the French institutions. For example, the elitist schools like “Sciences Po” or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89cole_Polytechnique&quot;&gt;Polytechnique&lt;/a&gt;, which “only educated notables’s children”. Children, which would later on, obtain high positions, for example, in embassies or in government. For Bloch, the elites were completely out of touch with the working class, the majority of the French population, and were only guided by their self-interest. Bloch also writes that “a country is suffering, when the people in charge of the public institutions are hostile to those very same institutions”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more personal level, two things in this book, caught my attention. First, the way Bloch writes. Even if this book is almost 80 years old, I found Bloch’s writing quite demanding, even compared to French authors from the 50s or the 60s. It probably has to do with the fact that Bloch, who was born in 1886, was a highly recognized historian and professor for whom language was not just a tool but something of the highest importance. I’ve had, at multiples times, even difficulties to understand some of his sentences. I don’t know anything about linguistics, but it is quite surprising to see how we can express ourselves so differently, even just a few decades apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing that caught my attention, is when the action in the book is taking place in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rennes&quot;&gt;Rennes&lt;/a&gt;, a city in Brittany, and especially when Bloch referenced the “Boulevard Sévigné”, one of the roads used by the German forces in June 1940 to enter the city. I lived in Rennes for quite some time, and I was, at one point, living in an apartment located on a street adjacent to the Boulevard Sévigné. Imagining someone sitting at his kitchen table eating breakfast, be surprised to hear tanks or at least some unknown large vehicles in the distance. And then, probably standing up to get a look out of one near window while thinking of the disastrous latest news of the war shared by a neighbour the evening before, and be even more surprised and speechless to see germans soldiers all over the place, just wandering freely in the city he’s been living for some years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Strange-Defeat-Marc-Bloch/dp/0393319113&quot;&gt;Strange Defeat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a really interesting book, from which a lot can be learn, even today. When Bloch wrote this book, France had just surrendered and its future was dependent of the good will of Adolf Hitler. But even those circumstances couldn’t totally affect Bloch, who was still hopeful and even confident that France would at some point get its sovereignty back. And also hopeful that when that day would come, the people in charge would make the necessary changes at every level of the society (politics, education, military…) to avoid history from repeating itself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As this is my first post, I just quickly want to explain what bring me to write it.</summary></entry></feed>